We've talked about using intents within Sunshine to start activities and send
data between apps. But what if you want to broadcast a message to
many apps? For example, the system will broadcast a message, saying that the
device is charging or that it's just finished rebooting. To do that ourselves,
we use the SendBroadcast method to broadcast an intent. And those broadcasts
are received by broadcast receivers, typically
referred to as simply, receivers. Using intent
filters, like the ones we saw earlier, they indicate which broadcast they're
interested in. So if we return to our envelope metaphor from earlier, in
the case of a broadcast intent, your
envelope is basically addressed to any broadcast receiver
that's interested in knowing that this event has
happened. And it does that using intent filter.
So intents, which are broadcast, are transmitted to every
app with a broadcast receiver that has an intent
filter telling the system your ideas are intriguing to
me and I wish to subscribe to end user.